Polish American Arts Association of Washington D.C. records 2000-2009 CPAA 02-10
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
Polish American Arts Association of Washington D.C. records
2000-2009
Polish American Arts Association of Washington D.C., Inc.
CPAA 02-10
1 box (0.5 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
Polish American Arts Association (PAAA) of Washington D.C. was established in January 1966, as an affiliate member of the American Council for Polish Culture. PAAA creates public awareness of Polish history and culture through lectures, concerts, films and art exhibits. Collection contains material that illustrates activities of the organization for the years 2000-2009.
Historical/Biographical Note
Polish American Arts Association (PAAA) of Washington D.C. was established in January 1966, as an affiliate member of the American Council for Polish Culture, an umbrella organization founded in 1948 in order to promote Polish culture in the US. At the beginning PAAA had about 20 members and currently it has reached 200. Membership is open to all and they support the organization through dues and engagement in various activities. Members are mostly Polish Americans but there are also Americans involved who are interested in promoting and fulfilling the mission of the organization. PAAA sponsors series of lectures and various programs like literary events, film festivals, concerts, and social gatherings. Since 1998, the organization has begun to offer scholarships.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Collection documents activities of the Polish American Arts Association in Washington DC area from 2000 till 2009. It contains minutes, treasurer reports, correspondence, flyers, and anniversary pamphlets covering these years. Newsletters were removed from the collection and placed with the Polish-American periodicals collection within the Connecticut Polish American Archives (CPAA). Collection contains also the American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs convention program booklet from June 14-18 1967, which was hosted by the Polish American Arts Association of Washington DC. Other related material to various social events and related documentation is also a part of the collection.
The collection is open for research.
The first part of the material in the collection was donated by Mrs. Estelle von Wachtel-Torres, who was a 1st vice president of the organization, in 2002. This collection is active and additional archival material is sent every year to the Connecticut Polish American Archives.
Search Terms
Polish American Arts Association of Washington; Polish Americans -- Washington (D.C.); Polish Americans -- Washington (D.C.)-- Societies, etc.; Minutes.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Newsletter.
Related Material
For related material see the following collections:
American Council for Polish Culture, CPAA 96-03
Arrangement
Material in the collection is arranged by date.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Letters to Connecticut Polish American Archives related to the donation of PAAA archives., 2002-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Council for Polish Culture Convention, hosted by the PAAA of Washington D.C., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Meeting minutes., 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Meeting minutes., 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Meeting minutes., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meeting minutes., 2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Meeting minutes., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Meeting minutes., 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Meeting minutes., 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Meeting minutes., 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Meeting minutes., 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting minutes., 2009 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence., 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence., 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence., 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence., 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Flyers, anniversary pamphlets., 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Flyers, anniversary pamphlets., 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Flyers, anniversary pamphlets., 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- PAAA Directory booklet., 2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Newsletter duplicates., 2000-2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)